The original head of Fortuna is made of white marble,
found at the Timacum Minus archaeological site,
The hair is combed in curls into a low bun, parted in the middle.
On the head of the goddess is a kalathus (basket-shaped cap, a basket).
Regular facial features, a high forehead, large eyes and pupils accentuated by a piercing
a straight, sharp nose and a prominent chin further emphasize the seriousness of the goddess.
The head was damaged during the bombing of Nis in 1944 when the cap was damaged.
Fortuna (Tyche in Greek mythology), was the goddess of wealth or fate,
and the embodiment of luck in Roman religion.
She was usually depicted with a rudder, a ball, a wheel of fortune and a cornucopia
or, as in this case, with a kalathus.